High Energy Physics Records UA204
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
High Energy Physics Records
1956 -- 1999
circa 1947 -- 2005
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
School of Arts and Sciences
High Energy Physics Program
UA204
16 Linear Feet
Conditions Governing Access
This collection contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into three series: Grant Files; Unprocessed accessions; and Richard Milburn records.
Biographical / Historical
Tufts University began experiments in the field of elementary particle physics when it was issued its first grant by the Atomic Energy Commission (AEC) in 1957. The original contract issued by AEC funded the study of hypernuclei and strange particles in emulsions, and set the foundation for a series of bubble chamber experiments. The High Energy Physics Group at Tufts received continuous grant funding from the AEC, which became the United States Energy Research and Development Administration (ERDA) in1974 until President Carter established the United States Department of Energy (DOE) in 1977.
Aside from bubble chamber studies, the High Energy Physics Group was also involved in the invention of the backscattered laser beam, experiments in collider physics, exploration of heavy quarks, investigations of high energy neutrino interactions, neutrino oscillations, and theoretical studies in particle phenomenology. While early researchers performed experiments using the Berkeley Bevatron, the group also carried out extensive studies at many high energy physics laboratories including the Brookhaven National Laboratory, the Cambridge Electron Accelerator (CEA), the Stanford Linear Accelerator Center (SLAC), Fermi National Accelerator Laboratory in Illinois, Rutherford Laboratory in England, the CERN SPS near Geneva, Switzerland, and now the CERN LHC. Most recently Tufts researchers have participated in proton-antiproton experiments using the Collider Detector at Fermilab (CDF), in the long baseline neutrino oscillation experiment MINOS (using the 730 kilometer neutrino beam, NuMI, from Fermilab to northern Minnesota), and in the ATLAS experiment at the LHC.
Notable faculty in High Energy Physics include Professor Jacob Schneps, who has been active in the program since its foundation, Professor Julian K. Knipp, Professor Richard H. Milburn, Professor Gary R. Goldstein, Professor W. Anthony Mann, Professor William P. Oliver, Professor Austin Napier and Professor Krzysztof Sliwa as well as Professor Allan Cormack who earned a Nobel Prize in Medicine in 1979. As of 2010, the Group is managed by two project directors, and employs eight faculty members. Research is contributed by faculty, visiting scientists, postdoctoral research associates, graduate and undergraduate students, and technicians. Tufts High Energy Physics Group plays a major role in advancing the global understanding of elementary particle physics through innovative research and development in the field. These advancements are supported by grants from the United States DOE, which the Group has successfully obtained for over fifty years.
Special thanks is also extended to Professor Jacob Schneps for offering his time and editorial input.
Custodial History
DCA Staff discovered three missing folders in box 1 of this collection in April 2014, after a patron had looked at it. The missing folders are: 001.00010 AEC budget, 1974; 001.00011 Progress report, 1973; and 001.00012, AEC budget, 1973. There were also loose papers stuffed in the back of the box. The staff deduced that these files were probably part of folder 001.00011 Progress report, 1973; the files were placed in a new folder and labeled as such, with a note stating what had happened. Two other folders were added to the box as placeholders for 001.00010 and 001.00012 with notes attached to them that explain that staff noticed the folders were missing in April 2014.
Staff looked through all other boxes this patron had viewed in a two week period before this discovery was made and did not find the missing folders.
Scope and Contents
The High Energy Physics (HEP) records include documents pertaining to U.S. Government contracts and grants issued to the HEP Group at Tufts University from 1957 to 2000. This collection contains proposals, budgets, correspondence, progress reports, foreign travel information and personnel data used to renew government contracts. These records track the annual projects and progress of High Energy Physics research at Tufts University. This collection also contains the records of Richard Milburn, a professor in the Physics Department who worked in the High Energy Physics program.
Curriculum and Instruction -- Academic Departments and Programs; Research and Research Administration
- Grant Files, 1956 -- 2011; 1958 -- 1999; UA204.001; 8.9 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series is composed of materials relating to the High Energy Physics Group's grant and contract activities. Included are proposals, budgets, correspondence, progress reports, foreign travel information and personnel data used to renew government contracts. These records cover the period between 1957 and 2000, with contracts and grants from the Atomic Energy Commission (1957-1974), the Energy Research and Development Administration (ERDA), and the Department of Energy (DOE).
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - [High Energy Physics Background - Budgets], 1957 -- 2010; UA204.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
    Comparative budget information for High Energy Physics compiled by Professor Schneps in fall 2009.
  - 1956-1975 [1 of 4], 1956 -- 1957; UA204.001.001.00002 (Box 1)
  - 1956-1975 [2 of 4], 1968 -- 1971; UA204.001.001.00003 (Box 1)
  - 1956-1975 [3 of 4], 1973 -- 1975; UA204.001.001.00004 (Box 1)
  - 1956-1975 [4 of 4]: Wallenmeyer - summaries of research and high energy manpower, 1971 -- 1975; UA204.001.001.00005 (Box 1)
  - 1975 [1 of 2], 1974 -- 1975; UA204.001.001.00006 (Box 1)
  - 1975 [2 of 2], UA204.001.001.00007 (Box 1)
  - 1974, UA204.001.001.00008 (Box 1)
  - AEC budget, 1974; UA204.001.001.00009 (Box 1)
  - AEC budget, 1974; UA204.001.001.00010 (Box 1)
    DCA staff discovered this folder was missing in April 2014. A placeholder folder with a note explaining this was inserted into the box.
  - Progress report, 1973; UA204.001.001.00011 (Box 1)
    DCA staff discovered this folder was missing in April 2014. A placeholder folder with a note explaining this was inserted into the box. There were also loose pages stuffed in the back of the box and DCA staff determined these were probably from this folder. The loose files have been place inside the placeholder folder that is labeled with this title.
  - AEC budget, 1973; UA204.001.001.00012 (Box 1)
  - AEC revised budget, 1973; UA204.001.001.00013 (Box 1)
  - AEC revised budget, 1972; UA204.001.001.00014 (Box 1)
  - AEC Phd and Grad students tests, 1969 -- 1972; UA204.001.001.00015 (Box 1)
  - AEC proposal, 1972; UA204.001.001.00016 (Box 1)
  - AEC Revised budget, 1971; UA204.001.001.00017 (Box 1)
  - Request for supplemental funds, 1971; UA204.001.001.00018 (Box 1)
  - Revised budget, 1971; UA204.001.001.00019 (Box 1)
  - AEC Progress report and proposal (originals), 1970; UA204.001.001.00020 (Box 1)
  - AEC proposal, 1971; UA204.001.001.00021 (Box 1)
  - AEC revised budget, 1970; UA204.001.001.00022 (Box 1)
  - AEC revised budget, 1969; UA204.001.001.00023 (Box 1)
  - Request for supplementary funds, 1969; UA204.001.001.00024 (Box 1)
  - AEC Proposal and progress report, 1969; UA204.001.001.00025 (Box 1)
  - AEC Nuclear technology request equipment grant, 1964 -- 1965; UA204.001.001.00026 (Box 1)
  - Request for supplementary funds and revised budget, 1968; UA204.001.001.00027 (Box 1)
  - Fundamental nuclear energy research report, 1968; UA204.001.001.00028 (Box 1)
  - AEC Proposal, 1970; UA204.001.001.00029 (Box 1)
  - AEC proposal, 1968; UA204.001.001.00030 (Box 1)
  - AEC Accounts, 1967; UA204.001.001.00031 (Box 1)
  - Request for supplementary funds, 1966 -- 1967; UA204.001.002.00001 (Box 2)
  - AEC Proposal: rough drafts etc., 1966 -- 1967; UA204.001.002.00002 (Box 2)
  - AEC Participation, 1966; UA204.001.002.00003 (Box 2)
  - Request for funds for film measuring machine, 1964 -- 1966; UA204.001.002.00004 (Box 2)
  - AEC Progress report, 1967; UA204.001.002.00005 (Box 2)
  - AEC request 2, 1966; UA204.001.002.00006 (Box 2)
  - AEC Accounts, 1965 -- 1966; UA204.001.002.00007 (Box 2)
  - AEC Progress Report, 1964 -- 1965; UA204.001.002.00008 (Box 2)
  - AEC, 1965; UA204.001.002.00009 (Box 2)
  - AEC Participation, 1965; UA204.001.002.00010 (Box 2)
  - AEC Accounts for (12-50-059), 1965; UA204.001.002.00011 (Box 2)
  - AEC Accounts 023, 1964; UA204.001.002.00012 (Box 2)
  - AEC Participation 12-26-005, 1964; UA204.001.002.00013 (Box 2)
  - AEC, 1964; UA204.001.002.00014 (Box 2)
  - AEC, 1963; UA204.001.002.00015 (Box 2)
  - AEC, 1962; UA204.001.002.00016 (Box 2)
  - AEC Accounts, 1963; UA204.001.002.00017 (Box 2)
  - AEC Confidential, 1963; UA204.001.002.00018 (Box 2)
    contains salary information
  - AEC, 1963 -- 1964; UA204.001.002.00019 (Box 2)
    This folder contains the 1963 Report of the panel on high energy accelerator physics of the general advisory committee to the AEC and the president's science advisory committee.
  - AEC Participation, 1962 -- 1964; UA204.001.002.00020 (Box 2)
    This folder contains AEC publication: "A statistical summary of the physical research program" for 1962-1964.
  - AEC budget, 1962; UA204.001.002.00021 (Box 2)
  - AEC, 1961; UA204.001.002.00022 (Box 2)
  - AEC (Accounts), 1961; UA204.001.002.00023 (Box 2)
  - AEC, 1959 -- 1960; UA204.001.002.00024 (Box 2)
  - AEC Accounts, 1959; UA204.001.002.00025 (Box 2)
  - AEC #1776, 1958; UA204.001.002.00026 (Box 2)
  - AEC, 1956 -- 1957; UA204.001.002.00027 (Box 2)
  - 1976 [1 of 2], UA204.001.002.00028 (Box 2)
  - 1976 [2 of 2], UA204.001.002.00029 (Box 2)
  - Budget, 1977; UA204.001.002.00030 (Box 2)
  - General, 1977; UA204.001.002.00031 (Box 2)
  - Proposal, budget, progress report, 1978; UA204.001.002.00032 (Box 2)
  - Consultant agreement, 1977; UA204.001.002.00033 (Box 2)
  - [Untitled], 1978 -- 1979; UA204.001.003.00001 (Box 3)
  - G. Goldstein Theory Proposal, 1978 -- 1979; UA204.001.003.00002 (Box 3)
  - Progress report (original), 1979; UA204.001.003.00003 (Box 3)
  - [Untitled], 1977 -- 1978; UA204.001.003.00004 (Box 3)
  - SLAC apartment, 1978; UA204.001.003.00005 (Box 3)
  - 1980 [1 of 2], UA204.001.003.00006 (Box 3)
  - 1980 [2 of 2], UA204.001.003.00007 (Box 3)
  - CCD Proposal A. Napier, 1980; UA204.001.003.00008 (Box 3)
  - Progress report and proposal: Master copies, 1980 -- 1981; UA204.001.003.00009 (Box 3)
  - 1981 [1 of 2], UA204.001.003.00010 (Box 3)
  - 1981 [2 of 2], UA204.001.003.00011 (Box 3)
  - Progress report - Original, 1981; UA204.001.003.00012 (Box 3)
  - Progress report: Master copy, 1978; UA204.001.003.00013 (Box 3)
  - 1982 [1 of 3], UA204.001.003.00014 (Box 3)
  - 1982 [2 of 3]: Prog. report master, UA204.001.003.00015 (Box 3)
  - 1982 [3 of 3]: Supplementary CCD proposal, 1981 -- 1982; UA204.001.003.00016 (Box 3)
  - TACUP report, 1982; UA204.001.003.00017 (Box 3)
  - TACUP presentation, 1983; UA204.001.003.00018 (Box 3)
  - TACUP, 1982 -- 1983; UA204.001.003.00019 (Box 3)
  - DOE TACUP, 1982; UA204.001.003.00020 (Box 3)
    This folder contains a historical summary of high energy physics at Tufts University.
  - TACUP papers, 1982; UA204.001.003.00021 (Box 3)
  - Final report: DE-AC02-76ER03023, 1983; UA204.001.003.00022 (Box 3)
  - DOE close-out, 1982; UA204.001.003.00023 (Box 3)
  - Talloires workshop, 1983; UA204.001.003.00024 (Box 3)
  - DOE contract [1 of 4], 1983; UA204.001.003.00025 (Box 3)
  - DOE contract [2 of 4], 1983; UA204.001.003.00026 (Box 3)
  - DOE contract [3 of 4], 1983; UA204.001.003.00027 (Box 3)
  - DOE contract [4 of 4]: progress report master, 1983; UA204.001.003.00028 (Box 3)
  - 1984 [1 of 3], UA204.001.003.00029 (Box 3)
  - 1984 [2 of 3], UA204.001.003.00030 (Box 3)
  - 1984 [3 of 3]: Lindgren sub-contract, UA204.001.003.00031 (Box 3)
  - Fire protection appraisal, 1977 -- 1978; UA204.001.004.00001 (Box 4)
  - ADP, 1972; UA204.001.004.00002 (Box 4)
  - ADP, 1973; UA204.001.004.00003 (Box 4)
  - ADP reports, 1974; UA204.001.004.00004 (Box 4)
  - ADP, 1974 -- 1975; UA204.001.004.00005 (Box 4)
  - ADP, 1975 -- 1976; UA204.001.004.00006 (Box 4)
  - ADP, 1977 -- 1982; UA204.001.004.00007 (Box 4)
  - DoE, 1985; UA204.001.004.00008 (Box 4)
  - DoE budget, 1985; UA204.001.004.00009 (Box 4)
  - Budget, 1984 -- 1985; UA204.001.004.00010 (Box 4)
  - Progress Report - Master, 1985; UA204.001.004.00011 (Box 4)
  - Proposal correspondence, 1985; UA204.001.004.00012 (Box 4)
  - [Proposed technical program and progress report], 1985; UA204.001.004.00013 (Box 4)
  - Foreign travel [1 of 2], 1978 -- 1986; UA204.001.004.00014 (Box 4)
  - Foreign travel [2 of 2], 1978 -- 1981; UA204.001.004.00015 (Box 4)
  - Cost management reports, 1981 -- 1982; UA204.001.004.00016 (Box 4)
  - DOE Statements of costs (Appendix C), 1984 -- 1987; UA204.001.004.00017 (Box 4)
  - Bacon Hill Lab Renovation, 1984; UA204.001.004.00018 (Box 4)
  - Contracts - DOE [1 of 2], 1976 -- 1985; UA204.001.004.00019 (Box 4)
  - Contracts - DOE [2 of 2], 1976 -- 1982; UA204.001.004.00020 (Box 4)
  - HEP Census, 1985; UA204.001.004.00021 (Box 4)
  - Notice of R and D outline, 1980 -- 1991; UA204.001.004.00022 (Box 4)
  - HEP Census, 1978 -- 1985; UA204.001.004.00023 (Box 4)
  - [Proposal and Progress Report], 1986; UA204.001.004.00024 (Box 4)
  - Proposal Correspondence, 1986; UA204.001.004.00025 (Box 4)
  - DOE Budget, 1986; UA204.001.004.00026 (Box 4)
  - Progress Report (master), 1986; UA204.001.004.00027 (Box 4)
  - Proposal correspondence, 1986 -- 1987; UA204.001.004.00028 (Box 4)
  - Progress Report Master, 1987; UA204.001.004.00029 (Box 4)
  - Budget; 2nd Revision, 1987; UA204.001.004.00030 (Box 4)
  - [Equipment Information DOE], 1987; UA204.001.004.00031 (Box 4)
  - DOE: Budget, 1987; UA204.001.004.00032 (Box 4)
  - DOE, 1987; UA204.001.004.00033 (Box 4)
  - Proposal Correspondence, 1988; UA204.001.004.00034 (Box 4)
  - Proposal (Master), 1988; UA204.001.004.00035 (Box 4)
  - Budget master copy, 1988; UA204.001.004.00036 (Box 4)
  - HEP - DOE Questionnaire, 1988; UA204.001.004.00037 (Box 4)
  - DOE site visit, 1988; UA204.001.005.00001 (Box 5)
  - Budget, 1987 -- 1988; UA204.001.005.00002 (Box 5)
  - Report, 1987 -- 1988; UA204.001.005.00003 (Box 5)
  - HEPAP Questionnaire, 1988; UA204.001.005.00004 (Box 5)
  - DOE :Proposal, 1988; UA204.001.005.00005 (Box 5)
  - DOE, 1988; UA204.001.005.00006 (Box 5)
  - TACUP Future / $ / Personnel / Cover Sheet, 1982; UA204.001.005.00007 (Box 5)
  - TACUP Report on Tufts' Task, 1983; UA204.001.005.00008 (Box 5)
  - TACUP Publications / first pages, 1982; UA204.001.005.00009 (Box 5)
  - Last 3 years TACUP, 1982; UA204.001.005.00010 (Box 5)
  - TACUP [1 of 2], 1982; UA204.001.005.00011 (Box 5)
  - TACUP [2 of 2], 1982; UA204.001.005.00012 (Box 5)
  - 1988, UA204.001.005.00013 (Box 5)
  - Accounting correspondence, 1986 -- 1988; UA204.001.005.00014 (Box 5)
  - Effort reports, 1984 -- 1988; UA204.001.005.00015 (Box 5)
  - Personnel forms PCA/PGE, 1986 -- 1988; UA204.001.005.00016 (Box 5)
  - Proposal master, 1989; UA204.001.005.00017 (Box 5)
  - DOE site visit, 1989; UA204.001.005.00018 (Box 5)
  - Proposal, 1989; UA204.001.005.00019 (Box 5)
  - Manpower census, 1988 -- 1989; UA204.001.005.00020 (Box 5)
  - Accounts, 1989; UA204.001.005.00021 (Box 5)
  - Report, 1989; UA204.001.005.00022 (Box 5)
  - Proposal papers correspondence, 1989; UA204.001.005.00023 (Box 5)
  - Budget revised, 1989; UA204.001.005.00024 (Box 5)
  - Progress report, 1989 -- 1990; UA204.001.005.00025 (Box 5)
  - HEP contract history, 1989 -- 1990; UA204.001.005.00026 (Box 5)
    This folder contains a historical summary of HEP at Tufts and an overview of Research.
  - DOE Census, 1990; UA204.001.005.00027 (Box 5)
  - Accounts (completed), 1990; UA204.001.005.00028 (Box 5)
  - Proposal correspondence, 1990; UA204.001.005.00029 (Box 5)
  - Budget, 1990; UA204.001.005.00030 (Box 5)
  - Technical Progress Master Copy, 1990; UA204.001.005.00031 (Box 5)
  - Scanners - RIF, 1990; UA204.001.005.00032 (Box 5)
  - K. Sliwa: OJI Award, 1990; UA204.001.005.00033 (Box 5)
  - Contracts [1 of 3], 1986 -- 1991; UA204.001.005.00034 (Box 5)
  - Contracts [2 of 3], 1990 -- 1991; UA204.001.005.00035 (Box 5)
  - Contracts [3 of 3], 1986 -- 1989; UA204.001.005.00036 (Box 5)
  - Report, 1990; UA204.001.005.00037 (Box 5)
  - CVs, 1991; UA204.001.005.00038 (Box 5)
  - Budget, 1991 -- 1992; UA204.001.005.00039 (Box 5)
  - DOE Budget Master, 1991 -- 1992; UA204.001.005.00040 (Box 5)
  - DOE: site visit, 1991; UA204.001.005.00041 (Box 5)
  - Proposal Correspondence, Misc., 1991; UA204.001.006.00001 (Box 6)
  - Proposal Master Copy, 1991; UA204.001.006.00002 (Box 6)
  - [DOE contract], 1991; UA204.001.006.00003 (Box 6)
  - Activity Summaries, 1991; UA204.001.006.00004 (Box 6)
  - PR and CVs, 1986 -- 1991; UA204.001.006.00005 (Box 6)
  - Progress Report, 1986 -- 1991; UA204.001.006.00006 (Box 6)
  - [Five year proposal correspondence], 1992; UA204.001.006.00007 (Box 6)
  - Subcontracting Reports, 1986 -- 1991; UA204.001.006.00008 (Box 6)
  - Budget Proposal Master [1 of 2], 1992; UA204.001.006.00009 (Box 6)
  - Budget Proposal Master [2 of 2], 1992; UA204.001.006.00010 (Box 6)
  - Proposal, 1992 -- 1997; UA204.001.006.00011 (Box 6)
  - Grant, 1992; UA204.001.006.00012 (Box 6)
  - Grant Revised Budget, 1991 -- 1992; UA204.001.006.00013 (Box 6)
  - Grant document, 1992; UA204.001.006.00014 (Box 6)
  - [Progress Reports], 1991 -- 1992; UA204.001.006.00015 (Box 6)
  - Foreign Travel Projections, 1987 -- 1992; UA204.001.006.00016 (Box 6)
  - Foreign Travel Reports, 1992 -- 1994; UA204.001.006.00017 (Box 6)
  - Foreign Travel [1 of 4], 1989 -- 1991; UA204.001.006.00018 (Box 6)
  - Foreign Travel [2 of 4], 1990 -- 1991; UA204.001.006.00019 (Box 6)
  - Foreign Travel [3 of 4], 1989 -- 1990; UA204.001.006.00020 (Box 6)
  - Foreign Travel [4 of 4], 1989; UA204.001.006.00021 (Box 6)
  - Revised Budget, 1993; UA204.001.006.00022 (Box 6)
  - Grant renewal request, 1992 -- 1993; UA204.001.006.00023 (Box 6)
  - [Tufts internal notice of award], 1993; UA204.001.006.00024 (Box 6)
  - Renewal budget materials, 1993; UA204.001.006.00025 (Box 6)
  - DOE, 1993; UA204.001.006.00026 (Box 6)
  - Proposal: Tech Program Final Master, 1993 -- 1994; UA204.001.006.00027 (Box 6)
  - Proposal Submission and Proposal Budget: Master Copies, 1994; UA204.001.006.00028 (Box 6)
  - Budget, 1994; UA204.001.006.00029 (Box 6)
  - Budget Material, 1994; UA204.001.006.00030 (Box 6)
  - Close-out of DOE Account, 1994 -- 1995; UA204.001.007.00001 (Box 7)
  - Revised Budget, 1994; UA204.001.007.00002 (Box 7)
  - Progress Report, 1993 -- 1994; UA204.001.007.00003 (Box 7)
  - Overview, 1994; UA204.001.007.00004 (Box 7)
  - Grant, 1994; UA204.001.007.00005 (Box 7)
  - 1994, UA204.001.007.00006 (Box 7)
  - DOE Revised Budget, 1994; UA204.001.007.00007 (Box 7)
  - Budget Supplement, 1995; UA204.001.007.00008 (Box 7)
  - DOE Budget and Proposal, 1994; UA204.001.007.00009 (Box 7)
  - (O'Keefe), 1994; UA204.001.007.00010 (Box 7)
  - Progress Report, 1994 -- 1995; UA204.001.007.00011 (Box 7)
  - Budget, 1996; UA204.001.007.00012 (Box 7)
  - Budget - Master, 1996; UA204.001.007.00013 (Box 7)
  - Proposal - Master, 1996; UA204.001.007.00014 (Box 7)
  - Revised Budget, 1996; UA204.001.007.00015 (Box 7)
  - Supplementary Requests, 1996; UA204.001.007.00016 (Box 7)
  - [CV of Principal Investigators], 1996; UA204.001.007.00017 (Box 7)
  - Grant: Document #15 1992 - 40702, 1974 -- 1997; UA204.001.007.00018 (Box 7)
    Contains DOE document University Contractor, Grantee, and Cooperative Agreement Recommendations for Announcement and Distribution of Documents from 1974 until 1997.
  - DOE Revised Budget:Master Copy, 1995 -- 1996; UA204.001.007.00019 (Box 7)
  - DOE Budget, 1996; UA204.001.007.00020 (Box 7)
  - HEPAP review [1 of 2], 1996; UA204.001.007.00021 (Box 7)
  - HEPAP review [2 of 2], 1996; UA204.001.007.00022 (Box 7)
  - Budget for 1997 DOE grant, 1996; UA204.001.007.00023 (Box 7)
  - [Proposal], 1996 -- 1997; UA204.001.007.00024 (Box 7)
  - Supplementary Requests, 1997; UA204.001.007.00025 (Box 7)
  - Supplementary Requests, 1997 -- 1998; UA204.001.007.00026 (Box 7)
  - DOE Grant Budget Proposal for 1997 and 1998-2002, 1996; UA204.001.007.00027 (Box 7)
  - Final re-budgeting for close-out of 520315, 1997; UA204.001.007.00028 (Box 7)
  - Proposal Master, 1997 -- 2002; UA204.001.007.00029 (Box 7)
  - [CV of Principal Investigators], 1997; UA204.001.007.00030 (Box 7)
  - Proposal Masters, 1997; UA204.001.007.00031 (Box 7)
  - Proposal- Color figures, 1997; UA204.001.007.00032 (Box 7)
  - Progress Reports, 1991 -- 1997; UA204.001.007.00033 (Box 7)
  - Proposal and budget: ATLAS, 1998; UA204.001.007.00034 (Box 7)
  - Proposal and budget :Supplementary Budget DOE Grant, 1998; UA204.001.007.00035 (Box 7)
  - Proposal and budget, 1997 -- 1998; UA204.001.007.00036 (Box 7)
  - Proposal and budget :Preliminary budget, 1998 -- 1999; UA204.001.007.00037 (Box 7)
  - Proposal and budget: Revised DOW budget, 1997 -- 1998; UA204.001.007.00039 (Box 7)
  - Proposal and budget, 1997 -- 1999; UA204.001.007.00040 (Box 7)
  - DOE budget proposals, 1999; UA204.001.007.00041 (Box 7)
    Contains ATLAS supplement 1999 and DOE Grant Revised Budget 1999 November 25, 1998.
  - [ Proposal and Budget], 1999; UA204.001.007.00042 (Box 7)
  - 1999, 1999 -- 2000; UA204.001.007.00044 (Box 7)
  - Progress Report, 1999 -- 2002; UA204.001.008.00001 (Box 8)
  - Progress Report, 2002 -- 2005; UA204.001.008.00002 (Box 8)
  - Progress Report and Proposal, 2005 -- 2011; UA204.001.008.00003 (Box 8)
- Additional accessions, 1976 -- 2011; UA204.002
  - Program records and grant files (1 of 3), 1977 -- 2011; UA204-001 (Box data_value_missing_e80a1f94f2f86090aaf4845407670c89, Box 1)
  - Program records and grant files (2 of 3), 1977 -- 2011; UA204-002 (Box data_value_missing_5c69dce4f70f00e7ec2506af5cc16636, Box 2)
  - Program records and grant files (3 of 3), 1977 -- 2011; UA204-003 (Box data_value_missing_9ed1fad30806dca3f264287afccea2d1, Box 3)
  - Grant proposals and progress reports, 1976 -- 2003; UA204-004 (Box data_value_missing_d4d521374b4683f2e3065b1a17c04cc5, Box 4)
    20 years from date of creation.
    Grant proposals for Department of Energy project continuation, 1995-2003, and progress reports for grant projects, 1976-2001.
- Richard Milburn records, circa 1947 -- 2005; UA204.003; 1.6 Linear Feet
  This series is arranged in received order.
  This series contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list. This series may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA for further details.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Transferred in 2016, accession 2016.119.
  This series contains the records of Richard Milburn, former professor in the Physics Department. His records include course files and notes (including student work), correspondence, projects relating to and documentation of the High Energy Physics program, and publications and reprints of his work.
  - Course files and notes, correspondence, High Energy Physics program documentation, circa 1955 -- 2005; UA204.003.013; 1.2 Linear Feet (Box 13)
    75 years from the date of creation.
  - Publications and reprints, circa 1947 -- 1992; UA204.003.014; .4 Linear Feet (Box 14)